# **Steve Niles**

Toronto, ON, Canada steve.niles@gmail.com https://www.steveniles.dev

I'm a full stack developer (front & back-end, desktop, library) using object-oriented and functional programming styles primarily in .NET. I'm most recently experienced with C# and Javascript, the React and AngularJS frameworks, and using parallel & asynchronous programming techniques.

## Experience

## Software Developer - Yangaroo

May 2019 - Jan 2021

- Create and enhance features of web-based Digital Media Distribution System
- Monitor and maintain deployments to development and testing environments
- Build and support public-facing dynamic web content

## Senior Developer - MRI Software

Aug 2013 - May 2019

- Architect & implement features for general & client-specific web-based systems
- Design & build in-house tools to improve development workflows & processes
- Set up & maintain virtualized development and testing environments

# **Part-time Object Oriented**

Jan 2013 - Apr 2013

**Programming Teacher** - Niagara College

- Instruct students in the use of Visual Studio and .NET using C#
- Teach object oriented programming techniques
- Guide and assess student performance

## **Computer Programming**

Sep 2007 - Apr 2013

# Research Assistant - Niagara Research

- Work on research and development projects in partnership with local businesses
- Projects include AutoCAD extensions and real-time remote sensing visualization
- Train junior developers in programming and image processing techniques

#### Education

# BSc (Honours) in Computer Science - Brock University

2009 - 2013

Courses of interest included:

- Artificial intelligence
- Algorithm analysis
- Compiler construction

# Computer Programmer Analyst Diploma - Niagara College

2006 - 2009

- Three year program
- Co-op with college's research department
- President's Honour Roll every semester

# **Open Source**

## **Jargon.Guard** - <a href="https://github.com/steveniles/jargon.guard">https://github.com/steveniles/jargon.guard</a>

Dec 2018 - Apr 2019

A set of simple guard clauses for method parameters

## The .NET Compiler Platform - https://github.com/dotnet/roslyn/pull/8195

Jan 2016 - Apr 2016

Found and fixed a bug in the static analysis code of Microsoft's .NET Compiler Platform

#### **MandelZoom -** https://github.com/steveniles/MandelZoom

Dec 2012 - Aug 2014

A fractal screensaver & small wiki guide on various issues relating to screensaver creation and fractal image processing